<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Great After School (GAS)]]></title>
  <link href="http://greatAfterSchool.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://greatAfterSchool.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-17T17:24:21-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://greatAfterSchool.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Fussell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spring Robotics Tournament!]]></title>
    <link href="http://greatAfterSchool.org/blog/spring-robotics-tournament/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-17T18:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://greatAfterSchool.org/blog/spring-robotics-tournament</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Steve Putz came up with the brilliantly simple and logical idea that GAS Robotics should launch with a Spring tournament.  This would not interfere with the FLL
season (FLL is in the autumn to avoid colliding with FRC), and actually spring is a better-for-schools time of year.  FLL always seemed backwards: you rush as
 soon as school starts and then do nothing (or I run a club) in the Spring.</p>

<p>Although very early in this process, if you are interested in hosting a 24 team tournament (or less, but 24 is pretty nice) or would love to participate in
a Spring tournament somewhere in the Bay Area, please contact me or anyone who is part of Los Alto Robotics.</p>

<h2>Suggested Format</h2>

<p>The best tournament I ever attended was run by Los Alto Robotics and had some very nice characteristics:</p>

<ul>
<li> It was simply &lsquo;In the afternoon&rsquo; running from Noon to about 6PM.  So you have lunch, go to tournament, get awards, go get dinner.</li>
<li> There was very little down time: teams ran through three pairs of tables and the judging pretty much continuously.  There were gaps (it wasn&rsquo;t a grind) but there weren&rsquo;t significant breaks.</li>
<li> During judging deliberation, guest FRC teams could visit or teams could present their projects to each other</li>
</ul>


<p>This was so pleasant that I would recommend it as a model.  Also since there is no subsequent event (e.g. a &lsquo;Regional&rsquo;) judging may be faster
or we could even simply drop the judging and just have kids <em>present</em> to everyone if they feel like it.</p>

<h3>Venues</h3>

<p>It would be nice if the venues were relatively consistent in format, but venues should be able to block out as many &lsquo;home slots&rsquo; as they need.  It is their venue after all.</p>

<h3>Team Registration</h3>

<p>Registration is done here:</p>

<ul>
<li> <a href="http://www.meetup.com/NorCal-Lego-Robotics-League/">http://www.meetup.com/NorCal-Lego-Robotics-League/</a></li>
</ul>


<p>It is first-come first-served starting 28 days (or something similar) before the event.  The cost per team could vary per venue due to facility costs.</p>

<h3>Other Thoughts?</h3>

<p>If you have any other thoughts or suggestions, just let me know and I will add them here.  Or join the meetup which has a forums capability.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Site Launch!]]></title>
    <link href="http://greatAfterSchool.org/blog/site-launch/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-16T18:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://greatAfterSchool.org/blog/site-launch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a bad week with the administration of FLL, I formally decided to launch GAS.  This site was live within minutes of that decision.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
